<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ashwin Vishnu's Website</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://fluid.quest/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://fluid.quest/</id><updated>2021-12-19T15:30:21+01:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>Testing comments on Fediverse</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/testing-comments-on-fediverse.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-19T15:30:21+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T15:30:21+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-12-19:/testing-comments-on-fediverse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A tiny javascript to backfeed replies&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/"&gt;https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.xmgz.eu/jekyll-mastodon-comment/"&gt;https://blog.xmgz.eu/jekyll-mastodon-comment/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fossacademic.tech/2021/12/16/CommentsTest.html"&gt;https://fossacademic.tech/2021/12/16/CommentsTest.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found a way to integrate comments from Fediverse into the blog. The
implementation is integrated into my Pelican theme. See 
&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/ashwinvis/m.css/commit/8ef74bdc10dfcef770a2be0ea48feb935a7df7e9"&gt;this
commit&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, I need to find a smart way to automate this workflow -- possibly using the
command line Toot client.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech Talk"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Global Climate Strike</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-09-24:/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
On September 24th many a soul around the world participate in a Global Climate Strike. Here I participate with some thoughts I wish to share. The only feasible solution to the Climate Crisis, is not a scientific one, but through policy. It is upto the ones in power - both in industry, finance and politics to make the right call, uproot the system and plant it anew. Why? I am glad you asked.  Let me explain…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;section id="do-not-despair-let-s-face-it-together"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do not despair, let’s face it together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes attitudes on facing Climate Change, there are three kinds of people. They may choose to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignore or downplay dangers of Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognize the dangers that await us, but tackle them objectively
rather than emotionally by making lifestyle choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take it as a personal crusade, making emotionally attached to the
crisis – which it is – and succumbing to negativity or anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which one is the right attitude? I would say all three are flawed
behaviours. My reasons are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignoring the dangers are what got us into the mess in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking personal responsibility is not enough to make a dent the
system (more on this later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protests do works in energising the people around you, but if it has
a detrimental effect if the result is nothing more than &lt;em&gt;be the
change you want to see in the world&lt;/em&gt; and then grieving over it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I should make it clear that the solutions that we should
focus on is a systemic, economic, industrial and political one. The
science has been clear for far too long. Waiting for a engineering
marvel to save us all is a foolish dream (i.e. it may not happen as soon as we
want it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="taking-personal-responsibility-does-it-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking personal responsibility - does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recall a conversation between graduate students in Earth sciences commenting
that it is uncomfortable when they go for a one-off mission on a research
vessel to the Arctic, because it is powered by diesel. Some things are
unavoidable, but some are not.  You are not alone. At some point in life I used
to believe so that if I make the right choices towards reducing my carbon
footprint would fix everything.  Less plastic. Less waste. Less cars. Less
electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Less is more&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;but not enough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am inclined to say that this is &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/jul/10/individuals-climate-crisis-government-planet-priority"&gt;not enough as a society&lt;/a&gt;.  Sure,
small gestures do help, but it always end up in the minority who try to fix
things. The cumulative effect as a society remains virtually unchanged.  Even
if we all choose not to fly, go vegetarian / vegan, consume less and basically
bide time – as most of us have done during Covid-19 pandemic – the emissions
continued to pile up to new &lt;a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/carbon-dioxide-levels-continue-record-levels-despite-covid-19-lockdown"&gt;record levels&lt;/a&gt;.
Why did it happen? It is a systemic issue. A vicious cycle which keeps the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2017/jul/10/100-fossil-fuel-companies-investors-responsible-71-global-emissions-cdp-study-climate-change"&gt;industry&lt;/a&gt;
(particularly the oil and gas, but also food, transport, energy, construction
and basically everything) functioning as it always had. Market forces such as
fossil-fuel subsidies (which still exists!) would delay the move to a clean,
sustainable society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/23/big-oil-coined-carbon-footprints-to-blame-us-for-their-greed-keep-them-on-the-hook"&gt;concept of carbon footprint&lt;/a&gt; was an invention of an oil
company originally intended to shift the blame onto powerless individuals.
Neither did I. At least now that is used to keep tabs on corporations! This
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yiw6_JakZFc"&gt;video essay&lt;/a&gt; by Kurzgesagt also discusses this issue at length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-much-time-do-we-have-left"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much time do we have left?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have conservatively &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor?tab=app"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; that at around 2030 we will reach the tipping point of 1.5 degrees warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor"&gt;&lt;img alt="How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C?" src="https://fluid.quest/images/global_temp_trend.png" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C? (Generated using
Copernicus Climate Change Service information [2021]. click to go to the web
app and see for yourselves)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now you should be convinced that this is an urgent matter. If not have a
look at web app above or &lt;a href="https://climateclock.net/"&gt;this infographic&lt;/a&gt; (Note: it plays some sombre music
when you click) or see the one below. Share your thoughts with your friends and
family. Talk about it. Make sure our voices are heard and our votes count. We
have little time left to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://api.climateclock.world/assets/widget-v2.js" async&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href="https://climateclock.world/"&gt;Climate Clock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;climate-clock/&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="FridaysForFuture"></category><category term="DigitalStrike"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>The Carpentries Instructor Training</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/the-carpentries-instructor-training.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-14T10:42:36+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-09-14:/the-carpentries-instructor-training.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have signed up to be trained as a certified Carpentry instructor and it has been wonderful learning experience so far. I received this information from Coderefinery and there are more &lt;a href="https://carpentries.github.io/instructor-training/training_calendar/#upcoming-instructor-training"&gt;upcoming online instructor trainings this fall&lt;/a&gt;. If you are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in Nordics or Estonia,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can attend the training on October 18-21, 4 hours in evening check your local time without any absence, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agree with the conditions to take the training (refer &lt;a href="https://amy.carpentries.org/forms/request_training/"&gt;https://amy.carpentries.org/forms/request_training/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reach out to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://coderefinery.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/300025-carpentries/topic/Announcement.20of.20new.20upcoming.20instructor.20trainings"&gt;https://coderefinery.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/300025-carpentries/topic/Announcement.20of.20new.20upcoming.20instructor.20trainings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to help you through the process. This priority would expire soon as NeIC's
membership of the Carpentries expire at the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Microblog"></category></entry><entry><title>The good old blog with a new name</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/domain-name.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-08-30T21:06:13+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-08-30:/domain-name.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought a domain name -- an address, a virtual place to call it home. The what, the how, the why and all those details for the curious.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR;&lt;/strong&gt; The URL of this website would soon be &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, on the thirtieth day of August 2021, as rain continue to shower on
Stockholm nearly every day, marks the end of my hunt for a succinct
domain name. For a long time, I was not convinced to spend a good handful of
money on a virtual asset. That changed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After jumping ships from Blogger, to WordPress, to Tumblr and finally to
&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; pages using Pelican static-site generator, I thought I was
done. I had full control on the content and the site generation. It was made
using open-source software, which means there was no way the toolchain will not
work in the foreseeable future. Therefore, in short the internals were intact.
Moreover, my precious visitors to my blog then do not get served ads, cookies
or third party tracking scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed fine. Until Microsoft bought it. Just because it is a free
service and has a large user base does not inspire any confidence that it might
stay like this forever. I recall how I used to adore following other blogs on
Google Reader until &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/"&gt;Google swung the axe, decided it was not profitable
enough&lt;/a&gt;. However, feed readers were easy, they
continued to exist, and it was still possible to find alternatives (server based
and server-less). In fact this is not an isolated incident. Large corporations
always change services, buy new ones, shutdown old ones on their whims and
fancies. They would come abruptly, and I should be prepared for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, blog and email servers are like
&lt;a href="https://genius.com/37517]"&gt;Hotel California (&lt;em&gt;You can check out any time you like, but you can never leave&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;
as long as you care about others to be able to find you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By buying a domain name, you get an address which stays the same,
irrespective of where you host it. The host could be GitHub, Gitlab,
&lt;a href="https://codeberg.page/"&gt;Codeberg&lt;/a&gt; or even a small server powered by a Raspberry Pi!
The readers will still be able to find you. And as a bonus, you can choose a
domain name which represents your interests better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about interests, did you know there are a lot of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;TLDs&lt;/a&gt; (top
level domain names) right now. Dull &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.net&lt;/code&gt; TLDs of yore are old-fashioned.
The prices can vary a lot! And there are a lot of gotchas to be considered in choosing
the "domain registrar". Where to buy can be confusing to a total beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="doing-the-pre-purchase-research"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#doing-the-pre-purchase-research"&gt;Doing the pre-purchase research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research that I did was a bit of informal hearsay in the interweb. For instance the &lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com"&gt;following comics by Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt; were really useful&lt;sup id="fnref:zines"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:zines"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="choosing a domain registrar" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/registrar/registrar.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="whois protection can" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/domain-privacy/domain-privacy.png"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;&lt;img alt="TLDs" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/tld/tld.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="subdomains" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/subdomains/subdomains.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this one on receiving
&lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com/comics/receiving-email/"&gt;emails&lt;/a&gt; which I will think
about later. Self-hosting emails is not an easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the choosing the domain registrar question, I got a excellent tip from
&lt;a href="https://jlelse.blog/dev/free-website"&gt;Jan Lukas-Else&lt;/a&gt; who had good experience
with &lt;a href="https://porkbun.com"&gt;Porkbun&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, I went there and there were many good deals
going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-i-bought-the-domain-name"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#how-i-bought-the-domain-name"&gt;How I bought the domain name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No single correct or optimal answer exists to which domain name one should buy
-- given the plethora of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;TLDs&lt;/a&gt; in the market! The &lt;a href="https://porkbun.com/products/domains"&gt;prices&lt;/a&gt; are
nearly fixed for a given TLD. This caught my eye, and I decided to scrap the
table for offline brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was a small &lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/ashwinvis/domain-name-search"&gt;domain-name-search Python tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing so, I was able to check availability of different combinations of
domain names using &lt;code&gt;whois&lt;/code&gt; and visualize costs in an interactive plot. Of
course, it was not perfect, a few domain names which were available were up for
premium registration (prices often exceeding thousands of dollars). Which were
not for me.  Once I had a shortlist done, it was easy to reduce the options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus I registered &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-fluidquest"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#why-fluidquest"&gt;Why &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I can say that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is an ode to the skill that I have been trained in for nearly a decade, Fluid Mechanics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The quest post Ph.D. still continues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-happens-next"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#what-happens-next"&gt;What happens next?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I will archive a snapshot of the landing page and this post, in case
someone runs into the blog years later with the old URL and receives a 404
error message, wondering what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will soon a register &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/about-custom-domains-and-github-pages"&gt;the apex domain / subdomain&lt;/a&gt; to point to this
very website via the &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;new URL&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully, all visits to the current URL
&lt;a href="https://ashwinvis.github.io"&gt;ashwinvis.github.io&lt;/a&gt; would be redirected by
&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; as long I continue to use their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a longer period of time, I can turn to a different host with more ethical
business model such as &lt;a href="https://codeberg.page/"&gt;Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="update"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#update"&gt;Update&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The move is now complete to &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:zines"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International licensed zines &lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com/licensing/"&gt;CC-BY-NC-SA 4.0&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:zines" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Show Your Stripes Day</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/show-your-stripes-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-06-18:/show-your-stripes-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hot everywhere. An info-graphic, a stark reminder that the worst is not over yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the COVID-19 pandemic is visible as vaccinations progress in most
places across the world, slowly but surely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="COVID-19 vaccinations progress across the world as of 2021-06-18." src="images/coronavirus-data-explorer.svg" style="width: 100%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Continent-wise share of people who received at least one dose of COVID-19
vaccine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;span&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ourworldindata.org/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; CC-BY 4.0, Our world in data&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I must be looking forward to a return to normality and a happy ending
as all children’s books end. However as all stories go, this is anything but
the end. Humanity has been thrust into a series of struggles in this modern
age. As I like to remind myself, it is humanity that needs saving — not life.
Life always finds a way. We have to ensure that we are not the architects of
our own doom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="https://live.staticflickr.com/4033/5160100668_fb96c15527_b.jpg" alt="Life Will Find a Way" style="width: 100%"&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00/5160100668"&gt;
  "Life Will Find a Way"
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00"&gt;JapanDave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;atype=html" style="margin-right: 5px;"&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we face the elephant in the room: the climate emergency, global heating
(erstwhile, global warming) is still on. It did not take a break during the
pandemic as most of us stopped commuting, travelling long distances and sat
home for several months at a stretch. Why? It’s because the energy production
and the economy continued to function as it has always been. A system with
little incentive to reduce emissions without sweeping tax reforms and
regulations to level the playing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to &lt;a href="https://nitter.snopyta.org/WMO/status/1405872275610554370#m"&gt;Show Your Stripes Day&lt;/a&gt; on 21 June, I took a moment to look at
all the places I have lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
   &lt;video controls autoplay width="100%"&gt;

       &lt;source src="/media/videos/stripes.mp4"
               type="video/mp4"&gt;

       Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
   &lt;/video&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://showyourstripes.info/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;,
      CC-BY 4.0,
      Professor Ed Hawkins (University of Reading)
   &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the regions highlighted above, France and Kerala (India) have a stark
contrast in the temperature anomalies in the past two decades. Naturally, in
France owing to heat waves, there has been a wave of climate activism in recent
years. I can vouch personally that summers in Kerala have been unbearable and I
had to install air-conditioning in my home — something that was avoidable in
my childhood. I also recall that during monsoon seasons of 2013 and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Kerala_floods"&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;
triggered low depressions, widespread torrential rains to such an extent that
dams had to be opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most climate scientists believe, if the heating continues and more
greenhouse gases are dumped into the atmosphere, unabated, then extreme events
would become more frequent. I believe that you are aware of all of this. The data
is clear. It is hot everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry></feed>