<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ashwin Vishnu's Website</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://fluid.quest/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://fluid.quest/</id><updated>2022-11-04T09:14:41+01:00</updated><entry><title>PyCon Sweden 2022 - Beyond 100% test coverage</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/pyconse2022.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-11-04T09:14:41+01:00</published><updated>2022-11-04T09:14:41+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2022-11-04:/pyconse2022.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lightning talk&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I hacked together a demo which is based on a real incident at work.
The incident made me realize that 100% code coverage is not good enough and one
has to resort to gradual typing in Python to avoid another class of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources to the demo can be found here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ashwinvis/beyond-100-test-cov"&gt;https://github.com/ashwinvis/beyond-100-test-cov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will add the transcript of the demo soon.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech Talk"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Email services</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/email-services.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-01-11T00:50:07+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-11T00:50:07+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2022-01-11:/email-services.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My current email server &lt;a href="https://protonmail.com"&gt;Protonmail&lt;/a&gt;, while reliable and easy to get started, ends up indirectly holding you hostage, if you need to add your own domain name, it comes with a steep cost of  € 48 per year (not to mention there is no official support for IMAP for the free tier). The next best option I had seen so far was &lt;a href="https://register.mailbox.org/en"&gt;mailbox.de&lt;/a&gt; with the same at € 36 per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://purelymail.com/"&gt;Purelymail&lt;/a&gt; is an interesting service offering this and much more at $ 10 per year. Looks like an indie operation from the website, but it does come with a compelling pricing. It is, however a US based company so all the privacy caveats attaches with the service. Although the company themselves do not sell any data, they do acknowledge the &lt;a href="https://purelymail.com/docs/security"&gt;limitations in their approach&lt;/a&gt;. Nevertheless I am curious to know how it goes for &lt;a href="https://jlelse.blog/"&gt;jlelse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Microblog"></category></entry><entry><title>Testing comments on Fediverse</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/testing-comments-on-fediverse.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-12-19T15:30:21+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T15:30:21+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-12-19:/testing-comments-on-fediverse.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A tiny javascript to backfeed replies&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thanks to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/"&gt;https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.xmgz.eu/jekyll-mastodon-comment/"&gt;https://blog.xmgz.eu/jekyll-mastodon-comment/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://fossacademic.tech/2021/12/16/CommentsTest.html"&gt;https://fossacademic.tech/2021/12/16/CommentsTest.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have found a way to integrate comments from Fediverse into the blog. The
implementation is integrated into my Pelican theme. See 
&lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/ashwinvis/m.css/commit/d5093d090f3e8458e53f5f4b534f757ffb311d57"&gt;this
commit&lt;/a&gt;.
Now, I need to find a smart way to automate this workflow -- possibly using the
command line Toot client.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tech Talk"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Global Climate Strike</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-09-24:/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
On September 24th many a soul around the world participate in a Global Climate Strike. Here I participate with some thoughts I wish to share. The only feasible solution to the Climate Crisis, is not a scientific one, but through policy. It is upto the ones in power - both in industry, finance and politics to make the right call, uproot the system and plant it anew. Why? I am glad you asked.  Let me explain…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;section id="do-not-despair-let-s-face-it-together"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do not despair, let’s face it together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes attitudes on facing Climate Change, there are three kinds of people. They may choose to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignore or downplay dangers of Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognize the dangers that await us, but tackle them objectively
rather than emotionally by making lifestyle choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take it as a personal crusade, making emotionally attached to the
crisis – which it is – and succumbing to negativity or anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which one is the right attitude? I would say all three are flawed
behaviours. My reasons are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignoring the dangers are what got us into the mess in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking personal responsibility is not enough to make a dent the
system (more on this later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protests do works in energising the people around you, but if it has
a detrimental effect if the result is nothing more than &lt;em&gt;be the
change you want to see in the world&lt;/em&gt; and then grieving over it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I should make it clear that the solutions that we should
focus on is a systemic, economic, industrial and political one. The
science has been clear for far too long. Waiting for a engineering
marvel to save us all is a foolish dream (i.e. it may not happen as soon as we
want it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="taking-personal-responsibility-does-it-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking personal responsibility - does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recall a conversation between graduate students in Earth sciences commenting
that it is uncomfortable when they go for a one-off mission on a research
vessel to the Arctic, because it is powered by diesel. Some things are
unavoidable, but some are not.  You are not alone. At some point in life I used
to believe so that if I make the right choices towards reducing my carbon
footprint would fix everything.  Less plastic. Less waste. Less cars. Less
electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Less is more&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;but not enough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am inclined to say that this is &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/jul/10/individuals-climate-crisis-government-planet-priority"&gt;not enough as a society&lt;/a&gt;.  Sure,
small gestures do help, but it always end up in the minority who try to fix
things. The cumulative effect as a society remains virtually unchanged.  Even
if we all choose not to fly, go vegetarian / vegan, consume less and basically
bide time – as most of us have done during Covid-19 pandemic – the emissions
continued to pile up to new &lt;a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/carbon-dioxide-levels-continue-record-levels-despite-covid-19-lockdown"&gt;record levels&lt;/a&gt;.
Why did it happen? It is a systemic issue. A vicious cycle which keeps the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2017/jul/10/100-fossil-fuel-companies-investors-responsible-71-global-emissions-cdp-study-climate-change"&gt;industry&lt;/a&gt;
(particularly the oil and gas, but also food, transport, energy, construction
and basically everything) functioning as it always had. Market forces such as
fossil-fuel subsidies (which still exists!) would delay the move to a clean,
sustainable society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/23/big-oil-coined-carbon-footprints-to-blame-us-for-their-greed-keep-them-on-the-hook"&gt;concept of carbon footprint&lt;/a&gt; was an invention of an oil
company originally intended to shift the blame onto powerless individuals.
Neither did I. At least now that is used to keep tabs on corporations! This
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yiw6_JakZFc"&gt;video essay&lt;/a&gt; by Kurzgesagt also discusses this issue at length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-much-time-do-we-have-left"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much time do we have left?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have conservatively &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor?tab=app"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; that at around 2030 we will reach the tipping point of 1.5 degrees warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor"&gt;&lt;img alt="How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C?" src="https://fluid.quest/images/global_temp_trend.png" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C? (Generated using
Copernicus Climate Change Service information [2021]. click to go to the web
app and see for yourselves)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now you should be convinced that this is an urgent matter. If not have a
look at web app above or &lt;a href="https://climateclock.net/"&gt;this infographic&lt;/a&gt; (Note: it plays some sombre music
when you click) or see the one below. Share your thoughts with your friends and
family. Talk about it. Make sure our voices are heard and our votes count. We
have little time left to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://api.climateclock.world/assets/widget-v2.js" async&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href="https://climateclock.world/"&gt;Climate Clock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;climate-clock/&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="FridaysForFuture"></category><category term="DigitalStrike"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>The Carpentries Instructor Training</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/the-carpentries-instructor-training.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-14T10:42:36+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-09-14:/the-carpentries-instructor-training.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have signed up to be trained as a certified Carpentry instructor and it has been wonderful learning experience so far. I received this information from Coderefinery and there are more &lt;a href="https://carpentries.github.io/instructor-training/training_calendar/#upcoming-instructor-training"&gt;upcoming online instructor trainings this fall&lt;/a&gt;. If you are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in Nordics or Estonia,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can attend the training on October 18-21, 4 hours in evening check your local time without any absence, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;agree with the conditions to take the training (refer &lt;a href="https://amy.carpentries.org/forms/request_training/"&gt;https://amy.carpentries.org/forms/request_training/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reach out to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://coderefinery.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/300025-carpentries/topic/Announcement.20of.20new.20upcoming.20instructor.20trainings"&gt;https://coderefinery.zulipchat.com/#narrow/stream/300025-carpentries/topic/Announcement.20of.20new.20upcoming.20instructor.20trainings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to help you through the process. This priority would expire soon as NeIC's
membership of the Carpentries expire at the end of October.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Microblog"></category></entry></feed>