<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ashwin Vishnu's Website - Blog</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://fluid.quest/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://fluid.quest/</id><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Global Climate Strike</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-24T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-09-24:/global-climate-strike-sept-2021.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
On September 24th many a soul around the world participate in a Global Climate Strike. Here I participate with some thoughts I wish to share. The only feasible solution to the Climate Crisis, is not a scientific one, but through policy. It is upto the ones in power - both in industry, finance and politics to make the right call, uproot the system and plant it anew. Why? I am glad you asked.  Let me explain…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;section id="do-not-despair-let-s-face-it-together"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Do not despair, let’s face it together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes attitudes on facing Climate Change, there are three kinds of people. They may choose to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignore or downplay dangers of Climate Change&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;recognize the dangers that await us, but tackle them objectively
rather than emotionally by making lifestyle choices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take it as a personal crusade, making emotionally attached to the
crisis – which it is – and succumbing to negativity or anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which one is the right attitude? I would say all three are flawed
behaviours. My reasons are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ignoring the dangers are what got us into the mess in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;taking personal responsibility is not enough to make a dent the
system (more on this later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protests do works in energising the people around you, but if it has
a detrimental effect if the result is nothing more than &lt;em&gt;be the
change you want to see in the world&lt;/em&gt; and then grieving over it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I should make it clear that the solutions that we should
focus on is a systemic, economic, industrial and political one. The
science has been clear for far too long. Waiting for a engineering
marvel to save us all is a foolish dream (i.e. it may not happen as soon as we
want it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="taking-personal-responsibility-does-it-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taking personal responsibility - does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recall a conversation between graduate students in Earth sciences commenting
that it is uncomfortable when they go for a one-off mission on a research
vessel to the Arctic, because it is powered by diesel. Some things are
unavoidable, but some are not.  You are not alone. At some point in life I used
to believe so that if I make the right choices towards reducing my carbon
footprint would fix everything.  Less plastic. Less waste. Less cars. Less
electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Less is more&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;but not enough&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I am inclined to say that this is &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/jul/10/individuals-climate-crisis-government-planet-priority"&gt;not enough as a society&lt;/a&gt;.  Sure,
small gestures do help, but it always end up in the minority who try to fix
things. The cumulative effect as a society remains virtually unchanged.  Even
if we all choose not to fly, go vegetarian / vegan, consume less and basically
bide time – as most of us have done during Covid-19 pandemic – the emissions
continued to pile up to new &lt;a href="https://public.wmo.int/en/media/press-release/carbon-dioxide-levels-continue-record-levels-despite-covid-19-lockdown"&gt;record levels&lt;/a&gt;.
Why did it happen? It is a systemic issue. A vicious cycle which keeps the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sustainable-business/2017/jul/10/100-fossil-fuel-companies-investors-responsible-71-global-emissions-cdp-study-climate-change"&gt;industry&lt;/a&gt;
(particularly the oil and gas, but also food, transport, energy, construction
and basically everything) functioning as it always had. Market forces such as
fossil-fuel subsidies (which still exists!) would delay the move to a clean,
sustainable society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know that the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/23/big-oil-coined-carbon-footprints-to-blame-us-for-their-greed-keep-them-on-the-hook"&gt;concept of carbon footprint&lt;/a&gt; was an invention of an oil
company originally intended to shift the blame onto powerless individuals.
Neither did I. At least now that is used to keep tabs on corporations! This
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=yiw6_JakZFc"&gt;video essay&lt;/a&gt; by Kurzgesagt also discusses this issue at length.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id="how-much-time-do-we-have-left"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How much time do we have left?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have conservatively &lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor?tab=app"&gt;estimated&lt;/a&gt; that at around 2030 we will reach the tipping point of 1.5 degrees warming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cds.climate.copernicus.eu/cdsapp#!/software/app-c3s-global-temperature-trend-monitor"&gt;&lt;img alt="How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C?" src="https://fluid.quest/images/global_temp_trend.png" style="width: 100%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;How close are we to reaching a global warming of 1.5˚C? (Generated using
Copernicus Climate Change Service information [2021]. click to go to the web
app and see for yourselves)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now you should be convinced that this is an urgent matter. If not have a
look at web app above or &lt;a href="https://climateclock.net/"&gt;this infographic&lt;/a&gt; (Note: it plays some sombre music
when you click) or see the one below. Share your thoughts with your friends and
family. Talk about it. Make sure our voices are heard and our votes count. We
have little time left to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script src="https://api.climateclock.world/assets/widget-v2.js" async&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;noscript&gt;&lt;a href="https://climateclock.world/"&gt;Climate Clock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/noscript&gt;
&lt;climate-clock/&gt;&lt;/section&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="FridaysForFuture"></category><category term="DigitalStrike"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>Show Your Stripes Day</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/show-your-stripes-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2021-06-18:/show-your-stripes-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hot everywhere. An info-graphic, a stark reminder that the worst is not over yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the COVID-19 pandemic is visible as vaccinations progress in most
places across the world, slowly but surely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="COVID-19 vaccinations progress across the world as of 2021-06-18." src="images/coronavirus-data-explorer.svg" style="width: 100%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Continent-wise share of people who received at least one dose of COVID-19
vaccine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ourworldindata.org/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; CC-BY 4.0, Our world in data&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I must be looking forward to a return to normality and a happy ending
as all children’s books end. However as all stories go, this is anything but
the end. Humanity has been thrust into a series of struggles in this modern
age. As I like to remind myself, it is humanity that needs saving — not life.
Life always finds a way. We have to ensure that we are not the architects of
our own doom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="https://live.staticflickr.com/4033/5160100668_fb96c15527_b.jpg" alt="Life Will Find a Way" style="width: 100%"&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00/5160100668"&gt;
  "Life Will Find a Way"
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00"&gt;JapanDave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;atype=html" style="margin-right: 5px;"&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we face the elephant in the room: the climate emergency, global heating
(erstwhile, global warming) is still on. It did not take a break during the
pandemic as most of us stopped commuting, travelling long distances and sat
home for several months at a stretch. Why? It’s because the energy production
and the economy continued to function as it has always been. A system with
little incentive to reduce emissions without sweeping tax reforms and
regulations to level the playing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to &lt;a href="https://nitter.snopyta.org/WMO/status/1405872275610554370#m"&gt;Show Your Stripes Day&lt;/a&gt; on 21 June, I took a moment to look at
all the places I have lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
   &lt;video controls autoplay width="100%"&gt;

       &lt;source src="/media/videos/stripes.mp4"
               type="video/mp4"&gt;

       Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
   &lt;/video&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://showyourstripes.info/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;,
      CC-BY 4.0,
      Professor Ed Hawkins (University of Reading)
   &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the regions highlighted above, France and Kerala (India) have a stark
contrast in the temperature anomalies in the past two decades. Naturally, in
France owing to heat waves, there has been a wave of climate activism in recent
years. I can vouch personally that summers in Kerala have been unbearable and I
had to install air-conditioning in my home — something that was avoidable in
my childhood. I also recall that during monsoon seasons of 2013 and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Kerala_floods"&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;
triggered low depressions, widespread torrential rains to such an extent that
dams had to be opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most climate scientists believe, if the heating continues and more
greenhouse gases are dumped into the atmosphere, unabated, then extreme events
would become more frequent. I believe that you are aware of all of this. The data
is clear. It is hot everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>Say yes to open-access + peer-review</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/open-access-peer-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-23T20:59:28+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-23T20:59:28+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2020-05-23:/open-access-peer-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The only model for peer-review which makes sense: the “No free view? No review!” signature campaign and why the existing publishing system needs an overhaul&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are fundamentally several problems with the current publishing model of
scientific articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors toil and work polishing nearly every word of the article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewers volunteer out of goodwill or to keep in touch with research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editors coordinate the whole effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libraries or businesses pay to get access to and distribute the end result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no-one above in this process gets paid. High charges do not make sense in
the electronic age, when fewer articles get actually printed into hard copy.
Even today with this model, as an author, you will have to pay extra to put a
colour figure which would not be legible in grey scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a documentary describing why this system is ridiculous at best and
predatory at worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups" title="Paywall - The Business of Scholarship" src="https://tube.tchncs.de/videos/embed/75ba36d5-1e81-4db4-95b0-8dd4790eb282" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;section id="a-paradigm-shift"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A paradigm shift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coalition-s.org/why-plan-s/"&gt;Plan-S&lt;/a&gt; and Bibsam consortium made a huge dent in this process. This movement gave
libraries and universities the ability and courage to collectively bargain and
walk out of the current subscription model with exorbitant prices. This was a
top-down change and resulted in new deals being made to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefit authors to make new articles open-access without the authors
paying a hefty Application Processing Charge (APC), but rather the university
as a whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make certain journals open-access or hybrid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we need now is a grassroots movement, a bottoms-up approach. As authors, we
should be willing to share our research at different stages to preprint servers
(for example, arXiv) and similar outlets (Zenodo, Figshare etc.). The
&lt;a href="https://www.sherpa.ac.uk/romeo/index.php"&gt;Sherpa-Romeo&lt;/a&gt; portal is my go-to tool in finding out what kind of article can
be archived for public-consumption. Also, check with your library to find out
if they could cover the APC charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as potential reviewers, this &lt;a href="https://nofreeviewnoreview.org/"&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; is relevant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://nofreeviewnoreview.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="No free view? No review!" class="m-image" src="/static/nfvnr-button.svg" style="width: 50%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is our turn as researchers and academics to say no to review articles
which would end up behind a paywall. It is simply not ethical in today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="research"></category><category term="open-access"></category><category term="academia"></category></entry><entry><title>Juggling roles as a parent / teacher / employee</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/juggling-roles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-20T11:13:51+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-20T11:13:51+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2020-04-20:/juggling-roles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Resources to keep your children entertained&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is not exactly lock-down in Sweden, but it is a voluntary work-from-home for
everyone. As a concerned parent, even if the preschools are open, we have
chosen not to send our preschooler to school. It is easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should share resources that my daughter found interesting, and I really
approve of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="apps"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#apps"&gt;Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.khanacademy.org/khan-academy-kids/"&gt;Khan Academy Kids&lt;/a&gt; - A
  really nice app with diverse tasks. Has enough material to function online and
  offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ur.se/tripp-trapp-trad"&gt;Tripp Trapp Trad&lt;/a&gt; - A tree with some fun
  activities around it.&lt;sup id="fnref3:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gcompris.net/index-en.html"&gt;GCompris&lt;/a&gt; - FOSS Educational
  cross-platform application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="videos"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#videos"&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.svtplay.se/kanaler"&gt;SVT play&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://urplay.se/bladdra/barn"&gt;UR play&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref2:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://invidious.snopyta.org/channel/UCQ00zWTLrgRQJUb8MHQg21A"&gt;Come Play With Me&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nfb.ca/channels/based-childrens-books/"&gt;NFB Canada Short films&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="things-that-i-have-not-followed-through"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#things-that-i-have-not-followed-through"&gt;Things that I have not followed through&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://keeplearning.khanacademy.org/daily-schedule#Pre-K-1-2"&gt;Daily Schedule from Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com"&gt;Varsity Tutors&lt;/a&gt; - Both paid and free lessons
  on a wide variety of topics themed as &lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com/virtual-school-day"&gt;Virtual School
  Days&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com/classes/featured-collections/virtual-field-trips?f_class_size=large-group0"&gt;Virtual Field
  Trips&lt;/a&gt;.
  I have signed up to see how it is like. The only trouble is to sign in to
  get access to the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden specific&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref2:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref3:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube channel&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>About my postdoc project at Stockholm University</title><link href="https://fluid.quest/project-eturb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:fluid.quest,2019-12-12:/project-eturb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;eTurb - Efficient simulations of turbulence in atmospheric boundary layers&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since October 1, 2019 I have been working as a postdoc at MISU, Stockholm
University. There has been a couple of meetings with the group involved, and
now the &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; are more concrete. I wrote a short abstract for
the &lt;a href="https://www.flow.kth.se/projects"&gt;annual FLOW catalogue&lt;/a&gt;, which I share
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eturb-efficient-simulations-of-turbulence-in-atmospheric-boundary-layers"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#eturb-efficient-simulations-of-turbulence-in-atmospheric-boundary-layers"&gt;eTurb: Efficient simulations of turbulence in atmospheric boundary layers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. V. Mohanan, G. Brethouwer, M. Kupiainen, J. Nordström, D. S. Henningson,
P. Schlatter &amp;amp; G. Svensson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding: Swedish e-Science Research Centre (SeRC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmospheric boundary layer (ABL) is the region which interacts with the
Earth’s surface and exchanges energy between larger geophysical scales and
land. The ABL goes through different regimes of stratification during the
day-night transition, referred to as the diurnal cycle. Daytime convection
results in a mixed layer when the boundary layer depth increases, and during
night as the land cools, a shallower stably stratified boundary layer is
observed. Accurate representation of turbulence in the ABL is crucial e.g. to
improve weather predictions and for wind-energy applications. A suitable tool
for studying the turbulence and complex transient phenomena in the ABL during a
typical diurnal cycle is large-eddy simulation (LES).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to tackle different modelling challenges along the road to an
efficient LES of the ABL. From the physics perspective, the wall boundary
condition and the LES subgrid-scale model need to be improved to allow for high
resolution simulations. Existing models should also be verified with regards to
numerical stability and consistency. A desired outcome of this project is an
efficient and accurate code for an LES of diurnal cycle of the ABL. To
coordinate this inter-disciplinary project a collaboration between KTH, SU, LiU
and SMHI is set afoot. For the LES we will use the Nek5000 (KTH and SU) and
ESSENSE (LiU and SMHI) codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="NikNaks [CC BY-SA 3.0 (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0)], via Wikimedia Commons" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Atmospheric boundary layer" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f1/Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg/512px-Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="postdoc"></category><category term="research"></category><category term="fluid-mechanics"></category></entry></feed>