<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ashwin Vishnu's Website - Blog</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ashwinvis.github.io/</id><updated>2021-08-30T21:06:13+02:00</updated><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title>The good old blog with a new name</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/domain-name.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-08-30T21:06:13+02:00</published><updated>2021-08-30T21:06:13+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:ashwinvis.github.io,2021-08-30:/domain-name.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought a domain name -- an address, a virtual place to call it home. The what, the how, the why and all those details for the curious.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR;&lt;/strong&gt; The URL of this website would soon be &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, on the thirtieth day of August 2021, as rain continue to shower on
Stockholm nearly every day, marks the end of my hunt for a succinct
domain name. For a long time, I was not convinced to spend a good handful of
money on a virtual asset. That changed recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After jumping ships from Blogger, to WordPress, to Tumblr and finally to
&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; pages using Pelican static-site generator, I thought I was
done. I had full control on the content and the site generation. It was made
using open-source software, which means there was no way the toolchain will not
work in the foreseeable future. Therefore, in short the internals were intact.
Moreover, my precious visitors to my blog then do not get served ads, cookies
or third party tracking scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything seemed fine. Until Microsoft bought it. Just because it is a free
service and has a large user base does not inspire any confidence that it might
stay like this forever. I recall how I used to adore following other blogs on
Google Reader until &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/"&gt;Google swung the axe, decided it was not profitable
enough&lt;/a&gt;. However, feed readers were easy, they
continued to exist, and it was still possible to find alternatives (server based
and server-less). In fact this is not an isolated incident. Large corporations
always change services, buy new ones, shutdown old ones on their whims and
fancies. They would come abruptly, and I should be prepared for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, blog and email servers are like
&lt;a href="https://genius.com/37517]"&gt;Hotel California (&lt;em&gt;You can check out any time you like, but you can never leave&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;
as long as you care about others to be able to find you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By buying a domain name, you get an address which stays the same,
irrespective of where you host it. The host could be GitHub, Gitlab,
&lt;a href="https://codeberg.page/"&gt;Codeberg&lt;/a&gt; or even a small server powered by a Raspberry Pi!
The readers will still be able to find you. And as a bonus, you can choose a
domain name which represents your interests better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about interests, did you know there are a lot of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;TLDs&lt;/a&gt; (top
level domain names) right now. Dull &lt;code&gt;.com&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;.net&lt;/code&gt; TLDs of yore are old-fashioned.
The prices can vary a lot! And there are a lot of gotchas to be considered in choosing
the "domain registrar". Where to buy can be confusing to a total beginner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="doing-the-pre-purchase-research"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#doing-the-pre-purchase-research"&gt;Doing the pre-purchase research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research that I did was a bit of informal hearsay in the interweb. For instance the &lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com"&gt;following comics by Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt; were really useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="choosing a domain registrar" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/registrar/registrar.png"&gt;
&lt;img alt="whois protection can" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/domain-privacy/domain-privacy.png"&gt;
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;&lt;img alt="TLDs" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/tld/tld.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img alt="subdomains" src="https://wizardzines.com/comics/subdomains/subdomains.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this one on receiving
&lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com/comics/receiving-email/"&gt;emails&lt;/a&gt; which I will think
about later. Self-hosting emails is not an easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the choosing the domain registrar question, I got a excellent tip from
&lt;a href="https://jlelse.blog/dev/free-website"&gt;Jan Lukas-Else&lt;/a&gt; who had good experience
with &lt;a href="https://porkbun.com"&gt;Porkbun&lt;/a&gt;. Therefore, I went there and there were many good deals
going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-i-bought-the-domain-name"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#how-i-bought-the-domain-name"&gt;How I bought the domain name&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No single correct or optimal answer exists to which domain name one should buy
-- given the plethora of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_Internet_top-level_domains"&gt;TLDs&lt;/a&gt; in the market! The &lt;a href="https://porkbun.com/products/domains"&gt;prices&lt;/a&gt; are
nearly fixed for a given TLD. This caught my eye, and I decided to scrap the
table for offline brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was a small &lt;a href="https://codeberg.org/ashwinvis/domain-name-search"&gt;domain-name-search Python tool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By doing so, I was able to check availability of different combinations of
domain names using &lt;code&gt;whois&lt;/code&gt; and visualize costs in an interactive plot. Of
course, it was not perfect, a few domain names which were available were up for
premium registration (prices often exceeding thousands of dollars). Which were
not for me.  Once I had a shortlist done, it was easy to reduce the options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thus I registered &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="why-fluidquest"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#why-fluidquest"&gt;Why &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;fluid.quest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, I can say that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is an ode to the skill that I have been trained in for nearly a decade, Fluid Mechanics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The quest post Ph.D. still continues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-happens-next"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#what-happens-next"&gt;What happens next?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I will archive a snapshot of the landing page and this post, in case
someone runs into the blog years later with the old URL and receives a 404
error message, wondering what had happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will soon a register &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/configuring-a-custom-domain-for-your-github-pages-site/about-custom-domains-and-github-pages"&gt;the apex domain / subdomain&lt;/a&gt; to point to this
very website via the &lt;a href="https://fluid.quest"&gt;new URL&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully, all visits to the current URL
&lt;a href="https://ashwinvis.github.io"&gt;ashwinvis.github.io&lt;/a&gt; would be redirected by
&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; as long I continue to use their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over a longer period of time, I can turn to a different host with more ethical
business model such as &lt;a href="https://codeberg.page/"&gt;Codeberg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="meta"></category><category term="software"></category></entry><entry><title>Show Your Stripes Day</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/show-your-stripes-day.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</published><updated>2021-06-18T16:06:06+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:ashwinvis.github.io,2021-06-18:/show-your-stripes-day.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is hot everywhere. An info-graphic, a stark reminder that the worst is not over yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The end of the COVID-19 pandemic is visible as vaccinations progress in most
places across the world, slowly but surely,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="COVID-19 vaccinations progress across the world as of 2021-06-18." src="images/coronavirus-data-explorer.svg" style="width: 100%" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Continent-wise share of people who received at least one dose of COVID-19
vaccine.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;span&gt;
&lt;a href="https://ourworldindata.org/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt; CC-BY 4.0, Our world in data&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I must be looking forward to a return to normality and a happy ending
as all children’s books end. However as all stories go, this is anything but
the end. Humanity has been thrust into a series of struggles in this modern
age. As I like to remind myself, it is humanity that needs saving — not life.
Life always finds a way. We have to ensure that we are not the architects of
our own doom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="https://live.staticflickr.com/4033/5160100668_fb96c15527_b.jpg" alt="Life Will Find a Way" style="width: 100%"&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00/5160100668"&gt;
  "Life Will Find a Way"
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;span&gt; by &lt;a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/56413961@N00"&gt;JapanDave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is licensed under &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.0/?ref=ccsearch&amp;atype=html" style="margin-right: 5px;"&gt;CC BY-NC-SA 2.0&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now we face the elephant in the room: the climate emergency, global heating
(erstwhile, global warming) is still on. It did not take a break during the
pandemic as most of us stopped commuting, travelling long distances and sat
home for several months at a stretch. Why? It’s because the energy production
and the economy continued to function as it has always been. A system with
little incentive to reduce emissions without sweeping tax reforms and
regulations to level the playing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to &lt;a href="https://nitter.snopyta.org/WMO/status/1405872275610554370#m"&gt;Show Your Stripes Day&lt;/a&gt; on 21 June, I took a moment to look at
all the places I have lived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
   &lt;video controls autoplay width="100%"&gt;

       &lt;source src="/media/videos/stripes.mp4"
               type="video/mp4"&gt;

       Sorry, your browser doesn't support embedded videos.
   &lt;/video&gt;
   &lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://showyourstripes.info/"&gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;,
      CC-BY 4.0,
      Professor Ed Hawkins (University of Reading)
   &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the regions highlighted above, France and Kerala (India) have a stark
contrast in the temperature anomalies in the past two decades. Naturally, in
France owing to heat waves, there has been a wave of climate activism in recent
years. I can vouch personally that summers in Kerala have been unbearable and I
had to install air-conditioning in my home — something that was avoidable in
my childhood. I also recall that during monsoon seasons of 2013 and &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2018_Kerala_floods"&gt;2018&lt;/a&gt;
triggered low depressions, widespread torrential rains to such an extent that
dams had to be opened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most climate scientists believe, if the heating continues and more
greenhouse gases are dumped into the atmosphere, unabated, then extreme events
would become more frequent. I believe that you are aware of all of this. The data
is clear. It is hot everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="climate"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>Say yes to open-access + peer-review</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/open-access-peer-review.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-05-23T20:59:28+02:00</published><updated>2020-05-23T20:59:28+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:ashwinvis.github.io,2020-05-23:/open-access-peer-review.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The only model for peer-review which makes sense: the “No free view? No review!” signature campaign and why the existing publishing system needs an overhaul&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are fundamentally several problems with the current publishing model of
scientific articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors toil and work polishing nearly every word of the article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewers volunteer out of goodwill or to keep in touch with research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editors coordinate the whole effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libraries or businesses pay to get access to and distribute the end result&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And no-one above in this process gets paid. High charges do not make sense in
the electronic age, when fewer articles get actually printed into hard copy.
Even today with this model, as an author, you will have to pay extra to put a
colour figure which would not be legible in grey scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a documentary describing why this system is ridiculous at best and
predatory at worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-scripts allow-popups" src="https://peertube.social/videos/embed/75ba36d5-1e81-4db4-95b0-8dd4790eb282" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;section id="a-paradigm-shift"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A paradigm shift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coalition-s.org/why-plan-s/"&gt;Plan-S&lt;/a&gt; and Bibsam consortium made a huge dent in this process. This movement gave
libraries and universities the ability and courage to collectively bargain and
walk out of the current subscription model with exorbitant prices. This was a
top-down change and resulted in new deals being made to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;benefit authors to make new articles open-access without the authors
paying a hefty Application Processing Charge (APC), but rather the university
as a whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make certain journals open-access or hybrid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we need now is a grassroots movement, a bottoms-up approach. As authors, we
should be willing to share our research at different stages to preprint servers
(for example, arXiv) and similar outlets (Zenodo, Figshare etc.). The
&lt;a href="https://www.sherpa.ac.uk/romeo/index.php"&gt;Sherpa-Romeo&lt;/a&gt; portal is my go-to tool in finding out what kind of article can
be archived for public-consumption. Also, check with your library to find out
if they could cover the APC charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And as potential reviewers, this &lt;a href="https://nofreeviewnoreview.org/"&gt;campaign&lt;/a&gt; is relevant:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href="https://nofreeviewnoreview.org/"&gt;&lt;img alt="No free view? No review!" class="m-image" src="/static/nfvnr-button.svg" style="width: 50%" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it is our turn as researchers and academics to say no to review articles
which would end up behind a paywall. It is simply not ethical in today’s world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="research"></category><category term="open-access"></category><category term="academia"></category></entry><entry><title>Juggling roles as a parent / teacher / employee</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/juggling-roles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2020-04-20T11:13:51+02:00</published><updated>2020-04-20T11:13:51+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:ashwinvis.github.io,2020-04-20:/juggling-roles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Resources to keep your children entertained&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is not exactly lock-down in Sweden, but it is a voluntary work-from-home for
everyone. As a concerned parent, even if the preschools are open, we have
chosen not to send our preschooler to school. It is easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should share resources that my daughter found interesting, and I really
approve of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="apps"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#apps"&gt;Apps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.khanacademy.org/khan-academy-kids/"&gt;Khan Academy Kids&lt;/a&gt; - A
  really nice app with diverse tasks. Has enough material to function online and
  offline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.ur.se/tripp-trapp-trad"&gt;Tripp Trapp Trad&lt;/a&gt; - A tree with some fun
  activities around it.&lt;sup id="fnref3:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gcompris.net/index-en.html"&gt;GCompris&lt;/a&gt; - FOSS Educational
  cross-platform application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="videos"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#videos"&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.svtplay.se/kanaler"&gt;SVT play&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://urplay.se/bladdra/barn"&gt;UR play&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref2:1"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://invidious.snopyta.org/channel/UCQ00zWTLrgRQJUb8MHQg21A"&gt;Come Play With Me&lt;/a&gt; &lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-ref" href="#fn:2"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nfb.ca/channels/based-childrens-books/"&gt;NFB Canada Short films&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="things-that-i-have-not-followed-through"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#things-that-i-have-not-followed-through"&gt;Things that I have not followed through&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://keeplearning.khanacademy.org/daily-schedule#Pre-K-1-2"&gt;Daily Schedule from Khan Academy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com"&gt;Varsity Tutors&lt;/a&gt; - Both paid and free lessons
    on a wide variety of topics themed as &lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com/virtual-school-day"&gt;Virtual School
    Days&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.varsitytutors.com/classes/featured-collections/virtual-field-trips?f_class_size=large-group0"&gt;Virtual Field
    Trips&lt;/a&gt;.
    I have signed up to see how it is like. The only trouble is to sign in to
    get access to the content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="footnote"&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:1"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweden specific&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref2:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref3:1" title="Jump back to footnote 1 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="fn:2"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube channel&amp;#160;&lt;a class="footnote-backref" href="#fnref:2" title="Jump back to footnote 2 in the text"&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="covid-19"></category></entry><entry><title>About my postdoc project at Stockholm University</title><link href="https://ashwinvis.github.io/project-eturb.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-12-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu Mohanan</name></author><id>tag:ashwinvis.github.io,2019-12-12:/project-eturb.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;eTurb - Efficient simulations of turbulence in atmospheric boundary layers&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since October 1, 2019 I have been working as a postdoc at MISU, Stockholm
University. There has been a couple of meetings with the group involved, and
now the &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; are more concrete. I wrote a short abstract for
the &lt;a href="https://www.flow.kth.se/projects"&gt;annual FLOW catalogue&lt;/a&gt;, which I share
below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="eturb-efficient-simulations-of-turbulence-in-atmospheric-boundary-layers"&gt;&lt;a class="toclink" href="#eturb-efficient-simulations-of-turbulence-in-atmospheric-boundary-layers"&gt;eTurb: Efficient simulations of turbulence in atmospheric boundary layers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A. V. Mohanan, G. Brethouwer, M. Kupiainen, J. Nordström, D. S. Henningson,
P. Schlatter &amp;amp; G. Svensson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding: Swedish e-Science Research Centre (SeRC)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The atmospheric boundary layer (ABL) is the region which interacts with the
Earth’s surface and exchanges energy between larger geophysical scales and
land. The ABL goes through different regimes of stratification during the
day-night transition, referred to as the diurnal cycle. Daytime convection
results in a mixed layer when the boundary layer depth increases, and during
night as the land cools, a shallower stably stratified boundary layer is
observed. Accurate representation of turbulence in the ABL is crucial e.g. to
improve weather predictions and for wind-energy applications. A suitable tool
for studying the turbulence and complex transient phenomena in the ABL during a
typical diurnal cycle is large-eddy simulation (LES).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to tackle different modelling challenges along the road to an
efficient LES of the ABL. From the physics perspective, the wall boundary
condition and the LES subgrid-scale model need to be improved to allow for high
resolution simulations. Existing models should also be verified with regards to
numerical stability and consistency. A desired outcome of this project is an
efficient and accurate code for an LES of diurnal cycle of the ABL. To
coordinate this inter-disciplinary project a collaboration between KTH, SU, LiU
and SMHI is set afoot. For the LES we will use the Nek5000 (KTH and SU) and
ESSENSE (LiU and SMHI) codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title="NikNaks [CC BY-SA 3.0 (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0)], via Wikimedia Commons" href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Atmospheric boundary layer" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f1/Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg/512px-Atmospheric_boundary_layer.svg.png"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Blog"></category><category term="postdoc"></category><category term="research"></category><category term="fluid-mechanics"></category></entry></feed>