<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ashwin Vishnu's Website - Tumblr archive</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/feeds/tumblr-archive.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://ashwin.info.tm/</id><updated>2015-03-29T13:15:09+02:00</updated><entry><title>Quote</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2015-03-29-so-many-places-movies-music-books-and-journal.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-29T13:15:09+02:00</published><updated>2015-03-29T13:15:09+02:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2015-03-29:/2015-03-29-so-many-places-movies-music-books-and-journal.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So many places, movies, music, books and journal papers. So little time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I know I can’t cover it in a lifetime.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Nirvana is overrated&lt;/strong&gt;. People invented it in the past because there was no internet and they got bored. Why break the circle when there is so much left to explore?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="rant"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry><entry><title>Random acts of Kindness</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2014-12-13-random-acts-of-kindness.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-13T10:55:03+01:00</published><updated>2014-12-13T10:55:03+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2014-12-13:/2014-12-13-random-acts-of-kindness.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I lost my access card to my lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Damn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It could have fallen anywhere in my 45 min. daily commute from my apartment to the university. I changed a bus and then took two metro trains. Practically untraceable. When I came back home, I turned my apartment inside out in vain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next day, I entered my lab with the help of my friend, Nasser. I asked him if losing the access card was a problem and whether I would end up paying a fine. He laughed and said, “No, it is fine. A lot of people lose it all the time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Getting a replacement access card was a hassle nevertheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I returned to my apartment, not realising I left my key hanging on the keyhole outside as I opened the door. A few minutes later, kind neighbours (who I barely knew, since I was new here), rang the bell, and handed the key to me, with a “be-careful” look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An hour later, I went down to go to the supermarket. And hey! There it was…. MY ACCESS CARD! Somebody figured out my address by searching online (In Sweden, all your contact details are public and open to all) and returned it. It was hanging on the notice board at ground floor. There was no message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="Lost and found access card!" src="https://78.media.tumblr.com/ea4cf12bdb4fce8e9ed9794d019da07d/tumblr_inline_pfjaz1p6R01t4yejq_540.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the stranger, who had the heart to return my card, thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Such random acts of kindness, without expecting gratitude is enough to spread happiness around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="kindness"></category><category term="strangers"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry><entry><title>House Nehru</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2014-12-05-house-nehru.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-12-05T22:47:05+01:00</published><updated>2014-12-05T22:47:05+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2014-12-05:/2014-12-05-house-nehru.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It just occurred to me how similar the Nehru dynasty fits in the world of Westeros, the Game of Thrones world. You might have already guessed by now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes I am talking about the all so proud House Stark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*spoilers alert*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rajiv Gandhi (Ned Stark) goes on a foreign trip to the south, Sri Lanka (Casterly Rock), so as to deal with regional politics. He ends up losing his life, unable to return to his home land. Becomes a legend in his nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sonia Gandhi (Katlyn Stark) pushes her favourite son to lead the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rahul Gandhi (Robb Stark) thrust into politics at a “tender” age, turns out to be way too emotional and inexperienced to meet the expectations of his bannermen. Loses way too many men in the elections, rendering his campaign against the BJP (Lannisters) a lost cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be more like Varun Gandhi (Theon Greyjoy) so on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coincidence?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian National Congress is way too “honest” to be House Stark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winter is coming. Enjoy… Merry Xmas!&lt;/p&gt;
</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="game of thrones"></category><category term="congress"></category><category term="indian politics"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry><entry><title>Ying-Yang</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2014-11-11-ying-yang.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-11T00:55:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-11-11T00:55:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2014-11-11:/2014-11-11-ying-yang.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The never-ending yearning for the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yes. That is not what it stands for. The Ying-Yang is a symbol to indicate duality and balance in the nature and universe. Light and dark, summer and winter, rich and poor, wealth and penury, and so on…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="Ying Yang" src="https://78.media.tumblr.com/badacaaac802bcdbcb02a08ea5c17482/tumblr_inline_pfjaz12wYf1t4yejq_540.png" style="width: 300px" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let me put you in my shoes on how I came up with this perspective. One month ago, I moved to this new place, new city, and a new life in Stockholm. The first month is always hard of course, no matter how much you have travelled, you will be in for surprises (right Jibu?). And this period, I had to live in a guestroom, from where I had to move out in 2 months’ time. This is rather unsettling and made me restless. I just wanted to get settled and be at peace asap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then again, hey, I thought of how it would feel like when things become routine like clockwork… that can be disheartening, as well sooner or later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It occurred to me that the Ying-Yang can also describe the world and us. We are always like those small circles in the Ying-Yang, switching sides every now and then. You could be the white circle, surrounded by darkness, looking forward eagerly to turn to light side; and the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This has happened to me before too, I enjoyed night life and happening street of cities when I used to be at home. And soon after I started living in one of the big metros (Delhi NCR), I got sick and fed up of the monotony and consumerist culture. Nothing can beat being at home, right? Maybe. (Until you spent 6 straight months or more at home doing absolutely nothing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it is all in our minds. This yearning keeps us pushing forward, ike an unseen force - that is the good news. This feeling is the root of all human ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just remember, even if you find yourself like that tiny white dot covered in pitch black darkness, shine on… because, we all look up to the stars that make the night sky beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="https://78.media.tumblr.com/5364013a8ce427f819d5a38a542dd7e7/tumblr_inline_pfjaz2lTaD1t4yejq_540.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="brainwaves"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry><entry><title>Quote</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2014-11-07-take-happiness-spread-joy-hurt-no-one-and-dont.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-07T23:44:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-11-07T23:44:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2014-11-07:/2014-11-07-take-happiness-spread-joy-hurt-no-one-and-dont.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Take Happiness. Spread Joy. Hurt no one. And don’t give in to sadness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;May seem like a very impractical, inhumane way to live by. But it is very logical and at the end of the day, you will be happy. With a mind without pain and full of joy, how will you ever hurt others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="motto"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry><entry><title>A World of Zombie Blogs</title><link href="https://ashwin.info.tm/2014-11-07-a-world-of-zombie-blogs.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-11-07T23:23:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-11-07T23:23:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Ashwin Vishnu</name></author><id>tag:ashwin.info.tm,2014-11-07:/2014-11-07-a-world-of-zombie-blogs.html</id><summary type="html"></summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;*sighs*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;ol start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;ol start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Denial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bargaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Depression&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Acceptance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kübler-Ross model (yeah, I googled it, and kudos to Wikipedia) of grief. Usually applies to terminally ill people and families under the face of sudden loss. But well it can apply to anything. Even writer’s block.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://bigfatpage.blogspot.com"&gt;My blog&lt;/a&gt; had went into a state of prolonged stagnation. And I felt that it had been neglected for too long that, that no post can save it from this coma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was time to reinvent, for renaissance!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img alt="Teenage mutant ninja turtles" src="https://78.media.tumblr.com/cd0354bfb47a24ff5a177cb46bba5e38/tumblr_inline_pfjaz1Tw2Y1t4yejq_540.png" /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To arms!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I knew tumblr existed. But when I first tried it, I found it too short, too cocky. Too twitterish - only not limited to 140 characters that’s all. But things have changed, blogs are becoming redundant in a fast shrinking world. If I don’t have time to write, how can I expect you to find time to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That doesn’t mean we stop to think&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is human nature to think and ponder. And the more out of the box we think, we push the limits of this ephemeral world of thoughts further. So I persist, with my big fat mouth. Bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Tumblr archive"></category><category term="helloworld"></category><category term="introduction"></category><category term="tumblr"></category></entry></feed>